<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Music_Instruments>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1YS9MDZP93857</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0006428320</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>John Taylor</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>The portfolio is fine except for the fact that the last movement of sonata #6 is missing. What should one expect? </review_text>
    <rating>3.0</rating>
    <title>Parts missing</title>
    <date>March 11, 2014</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A3TS466QBAWB9D</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0014072149</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Silver Pencil</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>If you are a serious violin student on a budget this edition has it all: Piano accompaniment low price urtext solo parts and annotations by Maestro David Oistrakh where Bach&#x27;s penmanship is hard to decipher.  Additions (in dashes) are easily distinguishable from the original bowings.  This is a delightful concerto that all intermediate level violinists should perform with a violin buddy.  Get your copy today along with The Green Violin Theory Ear Training and Musicianship for Violinists book to prepare for this concerto and for more advanced playing! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Perform it with a friend, today!</title>
    <date>June 6, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A3BUDYITWUSIS7</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0041291905</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>joyce gabriel cornett</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>This is and excellent edition and perfectly true to the orchestral version!  It makes playing Vivaldi a joy!  I uses this for a wedding and was totally satisfied with the accuracy! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Vivalldi&#x27;s Four Seasons</title>
    <date>October 14, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A19K10Z0D2NTZK</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0041913574</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>TexasCowboy</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>Perfect for someone who is an opera fan or a working musician.Aida:  Aida (sometimes spelled Ada pronounced ah-EE-dah is an Arabic female name meaning visitor or returning) is an opera in four acts by Giuseppe Verdi to an Italian libretto by Antonio Ghislanzoni based on a scenario written by French Egyptologist Auguste Mariette. Aida was first performed at the Khedivial Opera House in Cairo on 24 December 1871 conducted by Giovanni Bottesini.Overview: Aida an Ethiopian princess is captured and brought into slavery in Egypt. A military commander Radames struggles to choose between his love for her and his loyalty to the Pharaoh. To complicate the story further Radames is loved by the Pharaoh&#x27;s daughter Amneris although he does not return her feelings. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Full score: voice and orchestra</title>
    <date>September 23, 2010</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A14X336IB4JD89</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0201891859</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>dfjm53</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>How many Nocturnes does it contain? All of them? Some?Unable to determnine contents therefore hard to decide if this is what I need/want. </review_text>
    <rating>1.0</rating>
    <title>Unable to determine contents</title>
    <date>October 17, 2012</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A2HR0IL3TC4CKL</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0577088726</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>scarecrow </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>this was written for Carin Levine in 2008 but not premiered until 2011 at the Musica Viva Fest in Munich. .the work&#x27;s premise maybe about the arduousness nefarious of existence how we all Work at life at complexity at densities of differing lifeworlds. Ferneyhough&#x27;s music might suggest that these multiple dimensions of an ontology exist in diagonals across differing spectrums of human cognition how we come to think about an objectaisthetic shaped ones and expressionistic ones as his music.The work has a nice classical shapeand holds the romantic at bay a mere 7 plus minutes for Alto Flute a neglected wind cadre member.The work has gorgeous arresting moments with a great bounty of extended timbres-pointillistic bursts Klangfarben Sehr Kraeftig that you do grow weary of it is almost predictable now hearing these works you know they will inhabit a dense timbral space of mega-speed lines tossed in all registersstill one listens that gap Freud speaks about that we know we need this at some level. . .the music slowed at times for structural rigour.. .  we have a dramatic causality at play in the subject(the work&#x27;s title) the arduousness of pushing aspiring working toward something pleasurable illuminating or not How about emancipation from itselfI guess we need forget the production of surplus value hereineven with the rebellions in current urban areas today It has no place. . .  these constructions  are leftovers from modernity the gods still hover. . .gods that Ferneyhough has no power to dispel. . . . All are now commonplace for the new music literature of music.This music still sound quite stunning marvelous and evocative todayit is simple at some level direct unencumbered and violent with spit-tonguesgratuitous lines fluttertonguepercussive slap-keystremoli wistful glissandi harmonics fast filigreed lines and simply threadbare melos an austere fragment of what was a melody. . .Claudio Arrau said someplace that the performer the musician must emanate a work while playing music a struggle aesthetic or otherwise Sviatoslav Richter thought this grotesque to look at a musician playing the great music. It was ugly for him. . .You can hear Ms.Levine on youtube playing her work she is quite convincing you always need to impart an authoritysuccored in an emotive focus that the music itself has not succumbed to your own possession. You play the music it doesn&#x27;t play you. . . I&#x27;d hope though that music with this arduous construction and structural vigour that it would in fact come to possess the performer. . .it is one of the last libidinal pleasures remaining. . . </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>arduous indeed!</title>
    <date>June 14, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A2DHYD72O52WS5</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029231</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Amazon Customer </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>Greg Koch is a knowledgable and charismatic host. He is seriously fun to watch. The main problem with the video is the format. The lack of on-screen tab is a serious flaw. You have to watch very carefully have a good understanding of the minor pentatonic and  basic foundation of blues licks to even have a chance at gleening anything from this video.If you&#x27;re just starting out pick up the IN THE STYLE OF series. While this series has its limitations (incomplete songs due to copyright no doubt) it has on screen tab and each lick is played at a reasonably slow speed. In addition their web site has downloadable tab.However if you can hold your own in the minor pentatonic give this a try. It is quite a workout and you&#x27;ll find yourself a better player having taken on the challenge. </review_text>
    <rating>3.0</rating>
    <title>GREAT! BUT NOT FOR  BEGINNERS.</title>
    <date>June 24, 2005</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1MUVHT8BONL5K</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029347</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Amazon Customer </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>2 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>I bought this DVD and I&#x27;m returning it.  The description and editorial review are misleading.  This is NOT a Clapton video.  Certainly some clips from Clapton but generally this is a how to video.  Same applies to Clapton  The Early Years! </review_text>
    <rating>2.0</rating>
    <title>NOT CLAPTION MUSIC VIDEO!  A Learn How To Play Guitar LIKE Clapton</title>
    <date>October 15, 2005</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A15GZQZWKG6KZM</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029347</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Robert Wright</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>I was looking for a concert not instructions to play his songs. A total waste of money. It should have said that it was for instruction. </review_text>
    <rating>1.0</rating>
    <title>I was disapointed</title>
    <date>December 21, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A16WE7UU0QD33D</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029347</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>S. R. Mcdonald</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>1 of 8</helpful>
    <review_text>If you are an unabashed EC fan (as I am) you must own thispiece of history!! It takes you from the obscure artist he wasin the early yearsto the Mega-star he is today!! Your EricClapton library won&#x27;t be complete without it!! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Solo Years Revisited</title>
    <date>October 2, 2005</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>AXMWZYP2IROMP</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029355</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Alex</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>2 of 2</helpful>
    <review_text>I was carefull to choose this DVD because it had early work on it  but i was dissapointed by the level of instruction. Even though i feel it is aimed at beg. to intermed. players the guy who is &#x27;instructing&#x27; could really do a beter job of spelling out the riffs and runs. for example he might say&#x27;ok this song starts with some hammer-ons and pull-offs (plays riffs) and then goes into A7 to Gmaj&#x27; just as an example. This is frustrating because i end up rewinding many times to make sure im playing the correct notes- what would be so much better is if he took the time and effort to say &#x27; this run startes 2nd fret on the G  pull off to open G then...&#x27; and so on spelling out the notes. this assures accuracy and ultimately saves time and frustration ( I feel strongly about this because i have purchases other DVD&#x27;s that are dome that way and the difference is noght to day)Also not all songs are not complete- for example white room is missing solo- layla is missing outro solo so its just studies of the songs reallyAfter watching i kinda feel my money would have been beter spent on a book of TAB but at the end of the day i feel i will get a handle on the songs that attracted me to this DVD  but buyer be informed! </review_text>
    <rating>2.0</rating>
    <title>not great instruction</title>
    <date>November 9, 2012</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1MUVHT8BONL5K</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029355</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Amazon Customer </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>3 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>I bought this DVD and I&#x27;m returning it.  The description and editorial review are misleading.  This is NOT a Clapton video.  Certainly some clips from Clapton but generally this is a how to video.  Also applies to Clapton The Solo Years. </review_text>
    <rating>2.0</rating>
    <title>NOT CLAPTION MUSIC VIDEO!  A Learn How To Play Guitar LIKE Clapton</title>
    <date>October 15, 2005</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A6DCKXX4659CR</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029355</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Hotshot </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>2 of 2</helpful>
    <review_text>Unless you are someone who dosen&#x27;t have a clue and you mistake this DVD of Guitar Instruction for live Clapton Concert Footage: You will thoroughly enjoy this item.  This DVD is very well done: I would rate it excellent in the line of Signiture Licks instructional video. I would rate it up there with the Hendrix Learn to Play Songs from Are You Experienced video/DVD by Hal Leonard. This Clapton stroll down nostalgic lane is not as comprehensive as that but it is of the same superior quality.  I could have wished for more songs to be included but the ones that are included are must know songs for any Clapton student.  If you want live concert try the most recent Live at Albert Hall Reunion Concert : Even though the band seems uninspired and tired and the audiance seems way too subdued for a Cream concert the music is still vibrant. I&#x27;ve been playing for almost 30 years and Clapton is one of my favorite teachers.  I still found the DVD very helpfull.  Beginner or seasoned vet will find much practical information and tips herein.  The instruction is clear and conscise. The Songs are Great! The tips and tricks are informative.  I couldn&#x27;t let one misguided simpleton ruin this treasure for the rest of us. I highly recommend this DVD. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>CLAPTON GUITAR INSTRUCTIONAL : ROCKS !</title>
    <date>September 14, 2007</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A28YJZCV43ZWQW</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029355</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>James V. Signorile</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>3 of 3</helpful>
    <review_text>I&#x27;ve played guitar for over 40 years but it&#x27;s been mostly folk music and classical and I only got bitten by the Blues Bug about 2-3 years ago - and EC was the prime reason for that (and also for my initially starting guitar back in &#x27;67 when he was in Cream but I was looking at it more from a Rock than Blues perspective back then not understanding when I was 15 how Rock evolved and is based on the Blues).I first used this DVD to learn White Room and Sunshine of Your Love - Doug Bodouch is fantastic at playing and explaining how and why Clapton played it the way he did.  I was able to join a Blues Band playing lead guitar only a few months after buying this because of the proficiency I picked up by learning and playing along with Doug on these DVDs (I also got the Solo Years and Acoustic Classics).These are HIGHLY recommended by me and no where does it state these are lessons *BY* Eric Clapton (good luck finding that!).Jim </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>First rate lessons on Clapton classics</title>
    <date>March 26, 2008</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A2I4CV4PGZCNAF</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029355</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Josh Hayden</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>2 of 3</helpful>
    <review_text>This isn&#x27;t worth your money. Doug runs through each song in about three or four minutes he doesn&#x27;t give you time to learn it.Unless you&#x27;ve already mastered transcribing (and then why buy this dvd?) you&#x27;re going to be left to rewinding a million times to get the right notes.This is no better than a youtube video of someone playing a bunch of clapton songs.Doug doesn&#x27;t even show you the rhythm or other guitar parts! You&#x27;re left only knowing the lead!What sense does that make? </review_text>
    <rating>2.0</rating>
    <title>Don&#x27;t waste your money.</title>
    <date>April 20, 2010</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1M7OWNI93N1Y3</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029363</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>geronimo</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>1 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>As much as I like doug boduch as a guitar player and teacher All songs on this particular dvdwere not explained as they should have been. He plays at tempo then starts playing slow but without saying what fret string etc sould be played (no tab either)....On one part he even states: you play this chordover here and then you play this chord wow that was clear..go figure..Also NONE of the picking form or right hand patterns were explained when the picking part was intricate..Maybe it was a producer&#x27;s order to teach  this way but really I was very dissapointed I expected more. Since I own the tablature book I didn&#x27;t have any problem with following the dvd but if you don&#x27;t well you are in trouble. The dvd is a very good complement for the tab book or else SKIP it. </review_text>
    <rating>2.0</rating>
    <title>not very didactic</title>
    <date>April 14, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A2FEDDUHQAEN97</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029363</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>J. Drinks </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>1 of 3</helpful>
    <review_text>THIS IS NOT A CLAPTON CONCERT!!! IT&#x27;S AN INSTRUCTION MANUAL BY SOMEONE NAMED DOUG BODUCH TO TEACH YOU HOW TO PLAY IN THE CLAPTON STYLE. I WAS VERY DISAPPOINTED AND RETURNED IT UNOPENED </review_text>
    <rating>1.0</rating>
    <title>clapton acoustic</title>
    <date>May 31, 2005</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A338HVUM4AWJY7</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029363</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Joaquim Do M. Nt </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>8 of 8</helpful>
    <review_text>For those who may not know the Hal Leonard publications and the Signature Licks Series: this is not a DVD of an Eric Clapton show! This is an instructional DVD for those who wants to play acoustic guitar.The instructor is Dough Boduch a freelance guitarist teacher editor and recording artist. He teachs how to play (in the acoustic guitar) 8 of the Eric Clapton tunes presented in Eric&#x27;s CD/DVD Unplugged. Songs are: Change the World Circus Layla Malted Milk Nobody Knows You When You&#x27;Re Down and Out Signe Tears in Heaven and Walkin&#x27; Blues.I think the quality of the image is very good and clean. The sound is also great - when Dough Boduch plays the acoustic guitar he sounds almost as Eric Clapton in the CD/DVD.After presenting part of the music at the regular speed the instructor breaks it in several parts then explain and shows part by part of each song at a very low speed (sometimes more then once) in order to make you get to the point.There is also a chapter used to tune the guitar. The instructor is very good and explains very well. The DVD could be a little bit better if we could have the TABs of the songs but they&#x27;re available neither on the DVD nor on a web-site. It seems however that if you get the Hal Leonard Eric Clapton - Unplugged play along book you will get there - I haven&#x27;t check it yet.One interesting section of 15 minutes is dedicated to the techniques used by Eric Clapton and how he uses them: bending vibrato pull-off hammer on fingerpicking blues scales and C Minor scale.One more cool section is the jam along section where the video shows the instructor playing but you can&#x27;t hear him. Instead you can be Eric Clapton for a day and play the acoustic parts of the song in a Acoustic Guitar Karaoke.To summarize I found this to be an excellent instructional video specially for those who are Eric Clapton fans and who already have a knowledge in playng the acoustic guitar. Beginners (such as myself) will probably have to work a little harder before getting the most out of this DVD. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>This is an instructional DVD! A Great One!!</title>
    <date>June 17, 2007</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A16WE7UU0QD33D</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029363</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>S. R. Mcdonald</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 4</helpful>
    <review_text>No EC collection would be considered complete without theacoustic side of EC because the man himself is MUCH morethan just the electric guitar!! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Acoustic EC</title>
    <date>October 2, 2005</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>AKKQM6B0KI6F4</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634029363</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Thomas J. Chuchola</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>2 of 2</helpful>
    <review_text>Very disappointing. This was advertised to be a note-for-note lesson on selected Clapton tunes and it was not even close. There was no tab to support the little (and sometime inaccurate) portions of the songs that were listed. I sent a complaint directly to Hal Leonard but never received the courtesy of a reply. </review_text>
    <rating>1.0</rating>
    <title>Clapton Classics</title>
    <date>May 1, 2010</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1BX81N79C9BVT</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634050028</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Rick Valentine</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>I&#x27;m too busy using it to take time out to review it. I suggest that you get it I did. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>I&#x27;m lovin&#x27; it</title>
    <date>May 30, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A11ER3801T7KRP</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634055429</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>robert r.</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>This is a basic instructional DVD . If you are looking to learn buy the Tomas Cruz volume 12and 3 . Look no further . </review_text>
    <rating>2.0</rating>
    <title>Basic</title>
    <date>July 1, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A175UOHOVXRYMW</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634055534</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Diane E. Amov </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>1 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>So you have a pile of guitar instruction books maybe some videos too. Yet somehow you just can&#x27;t make progress in your studies. You look at the profusion of guitar instructional materials out there and wonder which one of them will finally turn you into a guitarist. Well wonder no more. Happy Traum&#x27;s DVDs are the only ones you&#x27;ll ever need. Traum is an experienced and engaging instructor who has the unique ability to zero in on potential problems and tell the student exactly how to overcome them. His lessons go quickly but he leaves nothing out. Follow his pace and his advice about when to shut off the DVD and go practice on your own and you&#x27;ll be handling those chord changes on time in no time. It&#x27;s time to move beyond G/C/D and become a real guitarist and these are the DVDs that&#x27;ll help you do it. This set is the jumping-off point for Traum&#x27;s many other instructional DVDs. Whether your interest is bluegrass country blues fingerstyle or whatever start here. You&#x27;ll get an excellent easy-to-understand grounding in guitar technique and theory. After that you can move onto one of Traum&#x27;s other DVDs to explore your favorite genre. Oh great! I&#x27;ve just re-read what I&#x27;ve written and I sound like some slick salesperson. I guess it&#x27;s because I&#x27;m so relieved. After two years of false starts I&#x27;m finally learning how to play. Thank you Happy Traum! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Frustrated No More!</title>
    <date>June 22, 2008</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A2P1Z9NUJ9H1RT</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634055534</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>music fan</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>Bought this for my grand son that just started playing guitar and I know from past experience with Homespun Tapes that this will really turn the light on for him...Thank you Happy Traum for introducing this brilliant teaching concept ! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>This is the ticket</title>
    <date>April 30, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1D1S69ZMKYCCV</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>daniel</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>great book... you should be aware of blues scales and have a little practice before using it but it will help you a lot. After a few exercises you&#x27;ll notice some improvement on your style..and 50 licks is more than what you need...cheers from Costa Rica...surf town :) </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>product review</title>
    <date>November 6, 2010</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A7R79JLQ5Q28M</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Eddie</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>While I did not enjoy Mat&#x27;s Blues Rock guitar soloing DVD I did enjoy this one.It is very straightforward with Matt playing  and explaining 50 blues licks. The licks start with turnaround licks and are easy to learn and incorporate into my own playing.One minor complaint is that there is no context for the licks other than what Mat mentions. I think it would be more beneficial to the player to actually listen to the licks in a musical context (i.e. played with a band or a backing track).This is a useful addition to the blues player&#x27;s (and student) arsenal. </review_text>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <title>Good collection of blues licks</title>
    <date>August 25, 2005</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A3T7SXCKJUYXT3</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>K. D. Shultz</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>4 of 4</helpful>
    <review_text>This was a very pleasant suprize i really enjoyed this dvd.It challenges you to learn and play these very usable and desireable blues licks.In this dvd are the great turnaround lick&#x27;s that have been used for years on some of the best blues solo&#x27;s  I instantly began using what i had learned from this dvd in my solo&#x27;s.The one drawback is the DVD menu i found myself back at the start menu many times.This is the type of dvd that helps you take your soloing to the next level.But if you are new to guitar this would be a frustrating rideI would estimate that the people who would benifit from this should be at least intermediate to advanced level....but everyone is different.This dvd is one of the best blues insrtuction i own. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Buy It ...and get out of a rut</title>
    <date>September 27, 2007</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1JZM0YIYHL6JW</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Leon C. Rodriguez </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>3 of 3</helpful>
    <review_text>I&#x27;ve been playing the blues for a long time so I wasn&#x27;t particularly inspired by any of the licks. I didn&#x27;t find the &#x27;gem&#x27; that I didn&#x27;t recognize to add to my vocabulary the one illusive moment i was looking for... nevertheless every one of these licks is the &#x27;meat and potatoes&#x27; vocabulary that can be used to talk the talk.  Mat does an outstanding job of guiding you through these 50 licks with real clarity.  I like that he uses the actual names of the notes instead of naming the string and fret for reference.  I can see that Mat&#x27;s a real musician and has a masterful handle on his axe. I went through it in about a week and had a good time doing it. I like that the DVD format defaults to the menu after the lesson to give you time it &#x27;fool around&#x27; with the lick and squeeze as much as you can out of it. I really enjoyed it.  Good stuff. </review_text>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <title>Well executed and professionally done</title>
    <date>April 8, 2010</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A372SXZ39TUWTZ</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Magellan </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>1 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>Mat and would not hit it off.  Instant personality clash for sure.  Then again I didn&#x27;t buy this DVD to make friends.  I bought it to learn blues.  50 good usable licks presented in a way that you can actually learn them.  Good camera angles the sound is fair.  Tab could be onscreen but I guess the booklet works just fine.  Just the thing for the early intermediate player.This DVD spends a lot of time in my player! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Finally, a Blues Guitar DVD with some MEAT!</title>
    <date>July 30, 2005</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A331DOWXV50UMT</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>RDD</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>Some really cool riffs that can be incorporated into your playing - Instructor could have spent a little more time explaining and breaking them down but I guess they had to stay within a certain allotted recording time </review_text>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <title>Nice Riffs</title>
    <date>November 2, 2010</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A16ZE9MJ0703UB</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Rea</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>This wasn&#x27;t for me..but for my husband who enjoys anything guitar. He learned some new ideas and enjoys going back to this and seems to learn something new each time. He is not a beginner and not a pro either. </review_text>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <title>Fun to learn some new ideas</title>
    <date>April 12, 2014</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A3DM7ADJV144TZ</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>s. mack</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>this is a cool video and has some killer licks in it but as stated above this is not for novices. it is very fast paced and unforgiving. great for the upper level intermediate who has maybe hit a bit of a wall and just needs some fresh ideas. </review_text>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <title>beware!</title>
    <date>April 13, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A2FIMQIKNOHFPK</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>S. White</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>1 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>I am a professional musician with over 17 years experience on guitar alone and this is the second DVD in this series I have bought now as I was so impressed with the first which was the Country licks. At the outset it should be said that these DVD&#x27;s are not for beginners sorry but that&#x27;s just the facts. This isn&#x27;t to say that a beginner cannot glean inspiration and work up to certain licks slowly but I would suggest this really suiting the intermediate player to advanced on some techniques.With my many years of playing I was already familiar with the techniques being employed on this DVD and found myself ripping some awesome licks in just a couple of hours after sitting down and viewing it. Even for an old dog like me I was learning how to lay down certain phrases I was always curious about but never got around to ... such as some of the faster flourishes.The sound and presentation are simple and yet excellent with both right and left hand views on screen at the same time. Mat Gurman does a fine job of breaking down the phrases and is technically excellent in his own right. I have had no issues with the Tab that comes with this DVD NOT matching up with what is being played ... every note was where it ought to be.A final note ... don&#x27;t be put off by the return to menu feature I have found this to be a smart addition to this series since it allows you to stay with that lick until you got it locked in before moving on without having the DVD race away from you while you are working things out. This also makes each lick easy to find and return to rather than having to scroll through to locate it!For this kind of value I plan on getting the Jazz and Rock DVD&#x27;s in this series - my vocabulary has really expanded in the time I have spent with this product and I am already an advanced player. If like me you are an experienced guitarist you may find you only need 10 or more of these licks but I&#x27;d be learning them all because they can often transform into other licks you create yourself.Killer series! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Get rhythm!</title>
    <date>September 24, 2007</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1QVR0ZIG59ZAG</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Thomas G. Sopchak </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>1 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>My Background:In order to level set you as to my comments here is a little about me. I have been playing pretty consistently for about 1.5 years. I still consider myself a novice guitar player. I know 1/2 dozen cords a few songs some typical beginner licks and have been practicing the A major and A minor pentatonic scales both in the first position. I am pretty good with those two scales. I have no problem reading most guitar tablature.What You Need To KnowThis is just my opinion. It is key that you can read guitar tablature. Also it would be VERY helpful if you knew many (more than I do) of the pentatonic scales and several of the positions for each (there are 5 positions for each scale). Mat (the instructor) only shows you one scale and in a single position (A Major Blues scale). He does this very quickly at the start of the DVD. It would also be very helpful if you are proficient at bends hammer ons pull offs and slides. You will also do better if you have some skill in a few different strumming techniques including muted tones. Clearly all of these are key elements of blues guitar (actually any guitar work) and he uses them in abundance.The Instruction and Licks:As I mentioned he does show one of the scales he calls the A blues scale. However he is all over the place on the fret board (uses far more than just this one scale) and if you don&#x27;t have some degree of proficiency in playing scales you will not get much from this DVD. He also shows you quickly how to tune a guitar. However I&#x27;m guessing that anyone who would remotely be able to use this DVD would already know how to do that.The licks he shows are very cool and if you can learn some of them they can be strung together to really jam. They range widely in level of complexity. There are a few that could be played by a beginner who has little experience (although they are the exception). Any beginner trying to learn these licks would have to be highly motivated and determined. Mat does include the tablature for each of the licks which is very good. In most places on the DVD he shows both of his hands so you can see the fret work as well and the picking. He does slow his playing down and for the most part you can figure out what he is doing. However he is so versed in what he is doing that he does sometimes make assumptions that you understand what he just did or what he is telling you. This is where it will be difficult for beginners.Bottom Line:Pretty cool DVD. With my current skill level I will be able to make some use out of it but by in large it is a little beyond me still. That said I am still very happy I bought it because I am sick of just practicing scales up and down up and down without doing anything cool. You can not even get 30 minutes of live guitar lessons for $10. The DVD is done well enough such that if you have some ability to play and want to check out some cool licks it is well worth the money. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Not For The Beginner Guitarist, But Some COOL Licks!</title>
    <date>August 21, 2007</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A2788UYAD532T</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634061801</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>WannabeClapton </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>8 of 1</helpful>
    <review_text>Having recently revived my desire to improve on the guitar I purchased this video. I had just purchsed another DVD with which I was very happy and decided that any decent guitarist needed some blues licks in their repertoire. I had a more difficult time following along with this one than I did on the previous purchase. This one comes with a hard copy of the Tabulature but I&#x27;m convinced that in many places the Tabs don&#x27;t match what he says to play or actually does play. That&#x27;s a little frustrating for me. I do give it 3 stars because I do think as I improve there will be some learning opportunities but at my current skill level it&#x27;s a bit over my head so that makes it not very valuable for now. Perhaps there should be a grading/age/skill level system like they do for kids&#x27; toys that allows for consumers to judge how advanced you need to be to get value from a product or if it&#x27;s even suitable. </review_text>
    <rating>3.0</rating>
    <title>Not as good as I had hoped.</title>
    <date>May 6, 2007</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1746NHDF3PF3H</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0634065459</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>T. Feldmann</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>3 of 3</helpful>
    <review_text>After performing bottleneck gospel/blues professionaly for the past 12yrs I&#x27;ve noticed a trend amongst my generation (30somethings) of players which concerns me greatly...wild fast sloppy playing sounds more authentic.  I have had numerous conversations with fellow players attempting to convince them that fast and sloppy playing isn&#x27;t more authentic it&#x27;s just fast and sloppy playing.Brozman makes it a point to address just that in DVD 1.  He states that the originators were trying thier best to play as clean as possible but due to bad strings bad guitars and pretty lowsy recording equipment it created a challenge to do so although many did achieve very clean playing (Tampa Red Blind Willie Johnson Robert Johnson etc.).DVD 1 is critical in learning the fundamentals of control both with slide and picking.  I highly recommend DVD 1 for any players.DVD 2 covers classic detla blues material Brozman style.  Plenty of tricks to be learned even if your not looking to sound like a Brozman copy.DVD 3 expands into more open tunings.  Again plenty of tricks to be learned.Whether these are too advanced for the beginner I cannot say because I&#x27;m not a beginner.  I can say that minutes into DVD 1 I wished I had these DVD&#x27;s when I was learning because it&#x27;s taken me 12yrs to acquire the skills I could&#x27;ve learned in months of working with these lessons.ALl in all these DVD&#x27;s will help get the wheels of creativity flowing in your own playing...and playing clean. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Outstanding!!!</title>
    <date>January 25, 2011</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A26LIKTL5KW29E</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739003755</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>3_Angels</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>7 of 7</helpful>
    <review_text>This is a two CD set each CD is 30 minutes long.  The second CD is for the music discovery book I love this CD it is just perfect for group music classes and it is a fun CD for kids to just listen to.  There are 25 songs: a hello song (mentions mozart mouse and beethoven bear) a goodbye song (could be used for any program) 8 rhythm instrument songs 5 movement/music appreciation songs and 8 listening/ear training songs.The first CD is essentially a book on CD of the music lesson book and I don&#x27;t see why you would ever use it because a teacher could read the story herself much more entertainingly. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Great music for preschool music classes</title>
    <date>June 5, 2008</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A4TE45TH7L2MW</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739003755</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>~AMH</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>4 of 4</helpful>
    <review_text>The Discovery CD has songs for singing and movement. There are some original songs as well as familiar tunes. The Listen and Sing examples are short easy songs to help students learn solfeggio syllables la-ti-so-re-mi. The Lesson Book CD tells the story of Mozart Mouse and Beethoven Bear exploring the magical music book as they learn to play piano. Children play with their plush toys and play piano/keyboard along with the lessons. The lessons are well organized and fun for very young children. Some of the songs on the Discovery CD include:Hello SongIf You&#x27;re Happy and You Know ItRacing CarClownin&#x27; AroundFinger Play SongHickory Dickory DockMexican Hat DanceBeethoven&#x27;s Rage Over the Lost PennyMozart&#x27;s Variations on Twinkle TwinkleOld MacDonald Had a FarmMister Elephant&#x27;s Funky DanceSousa&#x27;s Stars and Stripes ForeverGiant&#x27;s LullabyDo Re Mi Tapping SongMinuet in FBeethoven&#x27;s Symphony No. 5Twinkle Twinkle Little StarPut the Beat in Your FeetGoodbye Song </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Magical Music Book Story</title>
    <date>July 30, 2011</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A732DZLEGXSEQ</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739003755</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Jenny Lee</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>This CD is absolutely awesome. My daughter loves listening to the stories of Clara Schuman Cat Beethoven Bear and Mozart Mouse. There are stories to listen to as well as wonderful renditions of the songs in the book. They have two differently played songs which helped my daughter a lot. It would be nice to have one of the renditions have the songs sung. Having to learn 10 songs for her recital with every song using the same 5 notes made it difficult for her to remember them all as they sounded so similar. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>We LOVED this CD!!!</title>
    <date>May 18, 2012</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A142DE4DV7NKTQ</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739003755</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Lois Seeger </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>As a lifetime piano teacher I love this child-friendly piano method for young children. Content is rich with a variety of musical experiences. And I have fun too with Mozart Mouse and Beethoven Bear.Its great to see the level of interest and readiness of a student. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>the best for young chldren</title>
    <date>January 27, 2014</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>AAUUICXM1YE8L</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739003755</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Mary Chopin</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>Just like the previous reviewer says the two CD&#x27;s are great in contents. For some reasons however my set came with labels switched around.  The one that said Music Lesson Book 1 was actually for Music Discovery Book 1 and vice versa. There must have been a mistake at the manufacturer. </review_text>
    <rating>4.0</rating>
    <title>The two CD&#x27;s came mislabeled.</title>
    <date>February 17, 2011</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A153V2QD4BJT1Z</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739003755</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Musicmom</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>We are very happy with this series.  My son has special needs and benefits from music therapy weekly.  This series teaches about musical concepts with a story book format.  We also bought the companion CD and stuffed animals. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Great series</title>
    <date>March 24, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A2TKRYCS1POPOA</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739003755</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>NewMommy</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>We absolutely love this line of books. My 4 year old is now on the third set and playing away! It&#x27;s made her lessons fun and easy. And I love that she can play with the cd&#x27;s accompaniment. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>LOVE</title>
    <date>January 29, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A1IRFW13NXF08Z</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739003755</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>R. Davis</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>Since Music for Little Mozarts is based on the age group of 4-6 I am surprised that the music on the CD doesn&#x27;t have tempo options for beginning lessons.  Also I think there could be more &amp;#34notice&amp;#34 given on when the songs will start just seems to quick or hurried. </review_text>
    <rating>3.0</rating>
    <title>Rating Based on Experience of a 4 Year Old</title>
    <date>March 9, 2014</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A25UM6A6A4SEDT</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739037986</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>BrotherMike57 </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>I would recommend this DVD to anyone interested in the construction and the materials in which pick ups are made from.  The history of the Semour Duncan Company is fascinating.  Anyone wanting a basic understanding of how pick ups works do yourself a favior and buy this DVD. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>Great Information</title>
    <date>December 22, 2008</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>ADM67P7K66F41</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739037986</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Jeffrey Smith </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>This is a great video with lots to learn and see. It is basically a tour of the SD factory with interviews with the Duncans. This may have started out like a fluff piece documenting the company but I really liked it. SD shows how he changes out pick-ups very cool. And it has a great educational section on the development sound and design of their products. Good. Great info available elsewhere in print and on the web but if you like moving pictures and like a good guitar story then $20 for this video is worth it. </review_text>
    <rating>3.0</rating>
    <title>A behind the scenes look at one of the innovators of guitar pick-up technology.</title>
    <date>January 12, 2009</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A18C8JYM2161KE</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739037986</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>M. Balzano</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>2 of 2</helpful>
    <review_text>This was terrible. It gets right to the part you need to know to solder the pickups and then cuts and shows pickup already installed. I really dont see how anybody approved this for sale. If you are looking to learn how to install pickups and save yourself money at the guitar store - this DVD is worthless. Again the video footage cuts ahead at the critical point that would show you which wires to solder where. so disgusted. </review_text>
    <rating>1.0</rating>
    <title>Terrible - skips essential info to install pickups</title>
    <date>August 27, 2008</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>AK3MEBCSQ18LO</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739037986</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>R. Burns </reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>2 of 4</helpful>
    <review_text>I didn&#x27;t think it was worth the money !I have used his pickups and they are fabulous .......Buy his pickups but skip the DVD ! </review_text>
    <rating>2.0</rating>
    <title>seymour duncan guide to pickups</title>
    <date>February 9, 2008</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>A307SOXS9WP4GI</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739040251</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Bill Card</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>If you want to know how drummers that have made it actually drum you&#x27;ll want this video. If not you won&#x27;t. </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>This was a good video</title>
    <date>February 4, 2013</date>
  </review>
  <review>
    <unique_id>ASP16LVGFITDE</unique_id>
    <unique_id>2179</unique_id>
    <asin>0739040251</asin>
    <product_name>check it in meta dataset</product_name>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <product_type>Music_Instruments</product_type>
    <reviewer>Bill Moll</reviewer>
    <reviewer_location>Did not get</reviewer_location>
    <helpful>0 of 0</helpful>
    <review_text>As a drummer of 40+ years - (recovered but relapsing constantly) - Simon Phillips becomes my new hero with this video. His polyrythmic ambidexterity seems effortless and natural and his behind the scenes comentary and instruction are concise thorough and easily absorbable. A must-have DVD for any drummer desiring to improve his skill set. Five Stars! </review_text>
    <rating>5.0</rating>
    <title>A must-have</title>
    <date>October 29, 2010</date>
  </review>
</Music_Instruments>